Before we get started, always remember
that black conservatives are not real,
and the ones that are real are
unserious, insignificant, and unworthy
of my attention and yours. So this past
week, Jubilee released one black radical
versus 20 black conservatives. It's
latest in its very popular line of
debate porn videos where they take one
reasonable person and put them against
20 foaming at the mouth weirdos or one
foaming at the mouth weirdo and 20
mostly normal people. Believe me or not,
or just believe me because I'm about to
leak DMs on the screen. Jubilee was
actually interested in having me be the
person at the center of this madness.
And I won't lie, I was tempted. I was
flattered for a moment and thought
taking part in such a spectacle may be
kind of fun, but in the end, I didn't
want to risk the possible damage from
such an appearance. For one, y'all know
I'm not the greatest like on the spot
debater. I don't know how I would have
came off for such an appearance under
those circumstances unless I was just
allowed to sit there and roast [ __ ]
all day, which is really the only thing
I'd have wanted to do. And you can look
at some of the people that were on this
episode and you know I would have had
jokes already.
[Music]
Sam.
>> Now, the reason is that Jubilee is
trash. Y'all, I'm sure I'm not the first
person to tell you that Jubilee likes to
pretend as if it's providing an
important political commentary and
encouraging discourse, but in reality,
it's debate porn. It's ragebait
spectacle that does well in the
algorithm. I've said it before in other
videos, and I've even shared research
proving that this style of debate does
very little in terms of having like
useful discourse on political topics and
definitely doesn't change anyone's mind.
No one really learns anything or moves
from whatever position they had by
watching these types of debates.
Instead, it's for laughs. It's for shock
value. It's for good oldfashioned react
videos like this one kind of is not
going to be. But first, I do want to
give a couple of moments to the video
and a few flowers to Amanda Seals.
Amanda is a slightly controversial
figure for a multitude of reasons that I
want to get into. I personally feel like
Amanda tends to mean well, but she also
just lacks useful filters on what should
and should not be said or like what is
or is not appropriate and what makes
sense or doesn't make any sense. And
I'll leave it there. But I have to give
her flowers because Amanda has been on
the right side of politics and her time
during Hollywood, which is probably why
Hollywood is not calling as much as they
were before due to her political
stances. If there was ever a place for
Amanda Sills a specific type of intense
energy, this seems to be it. She was
like a fish in water. And from what I've
seen, cuz I haven't actually watched
much of this [ __ ] If it wasn't for the
fact that I knew I was going to make
this video, zero clicks for me for this
type of [ __ ] Go back to the first
statement of this video. But from what I
saw, good, clean entertainment. But to
explain why, as I said, black
conservatives, especially black
Republican types, as I'm sure much of
this was made up of, are never ever to
be taken seriously. During Jim Crow, the
black family was together
>> by anyone, especially black people who
tend not to. Black conservatives in this
particular ilk are pound-for-pound the
most overd discussed and over
represented faction in all of politics.
They represent a fraction of a fraction
of the electorate. Yet, they take up
tons of media attention because the
media is invested in presenting them as
if their political movement matters.
despite the fact that we have had a
literal generation of data showing you
that they do not. I promise I'm going to
be nice by the end of this video to the
black conservatives. But first, I have
so much so much smoke. I try not to make
these videos because I have nothing.
Usually have very little positive to
say, but here we are. You asked for it.
You didn't. But you earned it, right?
So, here's a couple of really important
things to remember about so-called black
conservatives. First, it's something I
covered in several videos. If you
haven't watched, please go watch the
videos I made about black conservatives
on the main channel. The point of these
videos is to illustrate the fact that
these goofy surrounding Amanda in this
room are not really black conservatives.
These are clowns. Most of these types of
negroes who want to build platforms as
black conservatives on social media are
not to be taken seriously and do not
represent real black conservatism. Black
conservatives are folks like a killer
Mike or 19 keys. That this is what
actual black conservatism looks like.
They're still wrong in a lot of ways,
but I at least respect where they are
coming from, and I believe in my heart
that they want what's best for black
people, even if I don't agree with their
tactics. They come from the legacy of
Booker T. Washington, who had a racial
uplift philosophy that was compared to
the philosophy of Web De Boyce, much
more conservative and much more inwardly
focused and less focused on agitating
the white structures for more rights and
resources. And this is the opposite of
what the goofies in this room are. These
are basically buck dancy sellout who
represent the interest of white
conservatism and white supremacy and
they know that there is a large market
for building a white audience via
political shucking and jing. This is why
I always think it's hilarious when I'm
accused of pandering to this mythical
all-white audience by people who don't
have actual arguments against my ideas
and don't actually watch my videos.
Y'all clearly don't know what an
all-white audience actually looks like
or what content catered towards white
people actually sounds like. It looks
and sounds like Candace Owens's content,
the Haj twins, Officer Tatum, etc. You
can look at the voting data. There's
always been way more white people on
that side of the political aisle to
pander to than anything that I'm doing.
And that's what these people are trying
to do. They're trying to shake Candace
Owens out of her spot or at least get
her to share a little bit. Maybe finally
Candace has [ __ ] up enough to put her
in a position where she can't beat down
other people. Cuadas is kept. Candace
Owens is the biggest crab in the barrel
and has not allowed any other black
conservative to get a spot higher than
her or even on her level for the last, I
guess, decade now. And this same overall
phenomenon is true for actual black
Republicans. Not a single one of these
black Republican figures in Congress who
do all this shucking and jing for Trump
represent majority black districts. They
all come from white districts in mostly
white states with the slight exception
being Tim Scott who was a senator in
South Carolina. But we know the black
politics in that state are kind of
cooked as well. And this is important to
understand and is all possible because
white folks as a whole know very little
about black political thought. So when
they see any of these videos where they
put five black Republicans with five
black liberals or progressives or
whatever you want to call them, in their
head they're thinking this is a
conversation between equal factions.
They don't think about the fact that
black Republicans represent like two,
three, at most 10 in the last couple of
years percent of the black voting
population. They are so insignificant,
but the media puts them on the same
playing field for very specific reasons.
And it's because white conservatives
have always sought out and value black
minstrels that they can have parrot
their racist talking points.
>> White people should complain about the
NBA. I'd get tired of
>> I wanted to be in the NBA,
>> right? I'd get tired of being a white
guy turned on this television with my
two white sons and we're watching all
these black guys run up and down and my
kids thinking I can't be that.
>> Yeah.
>> How fair is that?
>> Indeed like issues of race when these
get out there and say, "Well, look at
me. I ain't playing the victim. You got
to stop trying to be a victim." And you
know you're dealing with unserious
people because that's what half of these
folks seem to be talking about playing
the victim card as if black people
volunteered for that status and that
victims just produced themselves out of
thin air. By this don't be a victim
logic. If Amanda Sals would have got out
of her chair and slapped the [ __ ] out of
one of them, they should just focus more
on not being a victim and moving on from
the fact that they've been assaulted.
And mind you, someone one of you
watching this is fixing your mouth to
say, "Well, if you slap me in the face,
we're going to have a problem." And
shout out to Rodney Hinton. Right.
Right. Right. There's this moment where
Amanda goes in on this little boy who's
never seen a black barber chair. Of
course he hasn't. Right. And he mentions
that he's from Angola and Amanda has to
go in on what people are trying to call
an Adios or FBA talking point. So I have
to take a quick aside to address those
goofy groups who are also conservatives.
And they're not as bad as these people
on this stage. But it's complicated. But
I got to get into it because
understanding black conservatives
definitely requires you to understand
that there is this unique connection
with the black immigrant to black
conservative pipeline that cannot be
ignored. You don't have to be [ __ ] FBA
to have recognized that. In fact,
nonados FBA thinking people have
recognized this for years. First, let's
point out that Amanda Sills herself
would be called a tether by these people
any other situation. So her seemingly
taking their talking points is like a
great sense of cognitive dissonance that
they must be feeling in the moment. But
it's not that she took their talking
points. This is a criticism that black
Americans have had for certain some
black immigrants for a long time before
those populations got started. And it's
also just as true that black folks have
not always been the nicest to black
immigrants when they got here with whole
African booty scratcher jokes and
misrepresentation of Caribbean culture
in our media. so on and so forth. Under
capitalism and global white supremacy,
tension between black Americans and
black immigrants is expected and pretty
much required by the system and requires
ongoing analysis and discussion by good
faith people who want to address those
problems, not make them into scapegoats
for platforms that they're building with
white supremacists themselves. You've
seen black immigrants talk about this,
such as foreign man, and foreign land
who's Bohemian, Andrewism who's in
Trinidad, Colormind who's Nigerian.
Also, shout out to Jules, who did a
great video on this years ago, who's
from America. I say all this to say that
[ __ ] and FBA do not have a monopoly on
this analysis. They only have a monopoly
on the goofiness attached to it. The
problem is they take this valid critique
and attach it to this weird form of
antilack nationalism and xenophobia,
which is why they have been proven
multiple times have aligned themselves
with right-wing conservative and
anti-immigrant organizations, and never
with anyone to the left of them, not
even Democrats. But because so many of
us are thirsting for liberation, that
[ __ ] FBA stuff sounds good. It sounds
inspiring. I get it. A lot of us are
easily tricked by simple lies over
complex truths. And in an us versus them
mentality, we let them slide lies into
our ears and fees and don't want to
challenge it. Like the best example is
like this whole situation with Twilight
or Tyla or whoever talking about she
flopped because she didn't respect
Americans. But like every pop girly has
flopped for like the last couple of
years. Chloe Bailey is from Georgia. So
is Normani. They both sold just as
poorly. The Essencefest nonsense I saw
people talking about a couple of months
ago as if 300,000 black women haven't
lost their jobs in the last 6 months.
Maybe that's why Essencefest wasn't as
popping as it's been in previous years.
Causation correlation people. Quick
shout out to Cam James who's done
several videos on this topic now as
well. Uh go watch that. I'm in that one
if you just want to hear more about
that. But we got to get back to the
moving on. So Amanda hits something
clear and important about a lot of black
conservatives types which again as I
said earlier there is a high
representation of backgrounds like this
one young man. There's a high propensity
of black children of immigrants or
immigrants themselves that take on this
stance and they were often often not
always raised in white spaces apart from
black people. Candace Owens is
Caribbean. DJ Academics is Jamaican.
Amala Ebonei I'm not sure how to
pronounce her name. E e Punobi. Amala
Eponobi is another far-right culture
critic and I believe she's Nigerian.
Please don't get me into Emanuel I chose
nonsense. And I'm sure there's others
that I can think of, but you get the
point. Okay, so follow me for a second.
And this is stealing a bit from
conversations and analysis that I've
gotten from Foreman and Forland on the
topic. So please check out one of his
old videos. I'll keep in the
description. But there's a lot of
distinct experiences at play here. The
first is again that black immigrant
experience. Unless you're black from
like Europe or the UK or France or
something like that and even then it's
not the same. That black immigrant
experience or you're coming from the
Caribbean or straight from Africa makes
integrating into American black culture
a little difficult because you're coming
from an environment where everyone is
black. And that may not seem like a big
deal, but that's actually huge. If
you're from the Caribbean or Africa,
everyone you see on TV is black. The
presidents are black. The school
principles are black. The leaders and
celebrities are all black. the people in
your whole life have been black, both
good and bad. So, you're not taught the
same type of [ __ ] that we're taught
and we're forced to work out here in
America. You don't know what it feels
like to come up directly under white
supremacist structures. You've not
learned to attach race to intrinsic
value of an individual the same way a
black person growing up here in the US
might have. And you don't know the
effects of that. And this is not to say
that white supremacy doesn't affect
African or Caribbean communities. We all
know that skin bleaching is a thing that
happens way more outside of America than
it happens to black people in America.
Let alone the fact that the scars of a
colonization exists in all of these
nations. I'm not trying to make it seem
like there's no issues with white people
there. But existing alongside or in our
case, to be honest, under your
oppressors, having slave masters on your
money, the constant psychosis of having
to live under white supremacy and the
erratic responses you develop to it, you
don't understand until you get there.
And I've heard from multiple black
immigrants that same exact story that
before they get there, they see the
images of us in the media. They see how
we're depicted on TV and they think,
"Oh, we just don't know how to act and
we act crazy." And it's not until you
get here and you realize that you're
going to be grouped in with us that you
start to develop an understanding of
what it really feels like. And for some
some they try to find ways to separate
themselves out. Hence, this little [ __ ]
has not seen a black barber in at least
a couple of weeks, if his entire life.
And then we get to the black suburban
experience, which is similar to the
immigrant experience, but there are some
differences. But usually the key thing
is much like in that previous
experience, the parents are creating
separation between that person, that
child, and other black people. Your
parents either didn't care or didn't
think through what it would be like for
you to be the flying the milk. This boy
in particular is from Vermont, which is
unintentionally hilarious, and it speaks
to that specific experience that a lot
of black conservatives go through that I
empathize with in between the slander.
Black conservatives mostly just want to
belong somewhere. If you watch a
gathering of black conservatives and
listen to them in between the [ __ ]
they're greatly just looking for
community and acceptance. That's why
they be so goddamn happy when they get
around each other. But when they do get
around each other, all they talk about
is how nobody likes or accepts them
anywhere else. That skit from Kian
Peele.
>> Now, to speak more on diversity, I
present tonight's speaker,
>> Mr. Douglas Jackson.
[Applause]
That [ __ ] is real. That is how they talk
to each other when they get in community
with each other. And it's because black
conservatives, whether immigrant or not,
feel uncomfortable in black spaces
greatly because they have a lot of
internalized antilackness or and or they
fear that they will be rejected because
they don't know how to perform blackness
in the way that they perceive other
black people to be doing. And they often
aren't accepted in white spaces. But the
price of being in those spaces, even
when they are somewhat accepted, is to
have to constantly deal with racism and
microaggressions and general disregard.
So this creates this in between space
that I truly feel sad for.
>> You were afraid of losing some of the
first black friends you had.
>> Yeah.
>> And did that happen?
>> Most of them said they just couldn't
imagine me supporting someone like
Donald Trump. We just kind of quit being
friends. It wasn't necessarily univil.
We just kind of quit talking to each
other. Everyone wants to feel like they
belong somewhere. And it's got to hurt
to be rejected by your own people. And
for some some of these guys on stage,
what results is this combination of what
I perceive is bitterness, internal
antilackness, and open defiance. They
sometimes become trolls, like the first
big dude that clearly just wanted to get
up there and shuck and jive to get
attention. Then there's this one guy
here that I know was on the episode even
though he wasn't in the episode, but if
you show you can see the top of his head
and I know this was there. He must have
been too for even Jubilee. So they cut
his ass out. I guarantee you there's
like some snippets there where they was
like, "Look, we just got to get this
[ __ ] off the episode. He just can't be
here." Understand that historically
black people have always lived amongst
each other. Even if you were black with
money, things like red lining and just
the way that cities were structured
meant that you would have money still
amongst every other class of black
person that existed in your area. It's
not like with white people where there's
a clear separation of classes except for
places like here in Atlanta. For the
most part, black folks live with other
black folks regardless of social
economic status. And this shapes black
culture in a lot of ways, but one of the
key things for this video is that it
does create a unified sense of being and
a sense of pride and love for blackness.
But if all of that is foreign to you,
because you grew up only around white
people, even the nicest ones in the
world are probably going to have you
develop a lot of isms and insecurities
about who you are. And so what do you
do? For many, you find ways to separate.
You begin to mimic the oppressor, hoping
to avoid being targeted by their
oppression. you develop pickme
tendencies like all oppressed groups do.
This is not something just for black
people. This is every minority group in
this country and really around the
world. This also includes sexual
minorities because the Pikmi falsy
believes that whiteness or straightness
or sisness or whatever it is is
inherently good and fair and virtuous
and that if only certain members of
their group wouldn't be so ghetto,
wouldn't be so bombastic and would just
assimilate that white people would stop
being racist. This is why talking points
around bootstraps and victim mentality
and personal responsibility are very
valued, but never something like
reparations, which if you're thinking
about the concept of accountability and
personal responsibility, this country
has never held itself accountable for
what slavery was. And then when you
point out complete facts about racial
discrimination that's still ongoing and
has barely changed, they want to change
the topic altogether. They will say
something like, "Well, if you stop
playing the race card, then this
wouldn't be such a big issue." They
delude themselves with this because they
know deep down white people will never
submit to being accountable for racism.
They've experienced it firsthand from
teachers, their friends, maybe even
their parents, and loved ones in some
cases. And they deal with it anyway
because they can't imagine a better
situation. So they turn all the trauma
and anguish from that against people
whose blackness does not fit into the
narrative that they've constructed for
themselves. And this is why so many of
them have shitty hair. So as create as
much distance as possible between them
and other black people. It's much easier
to turn that hatred against other black
people for not assimilating, for daring
to agitate against white racism than it
is toward the actual perpetrators of
racism that they keep on saying should
not be held accountable for victimizing
other people. They're always talking
about stop being victims but never have
the courage to face the predators in the
equation. Often get accused of thinking
that like I'm the authority on black
people or something like that. Only
and white people think that actual
[ __ ] don't feel that way. They may or
may not agree with me, but I'm not
speaking in any fashion that people who
are actually in community with black
people feel is out of turn. When I hear
people say FD thinks he knows everything
about black stuff, it's because I know
you think that [ __ ] because you not
around black people and don't know [ __ ]
about what's going on. And at the end of
the day to try to end with some sense of
olive branch. I feel a sense of pity and
sadness for those folks because I
understand that plight well enough. I
that wasn't my experience, but I've been
close enough to it to know that it's not
easy to be in that in between place and
to feel like black people are rejecting
you and feel like white people are
rejecting you and not know what to do.
Don't get me wrong, I have all the smoke
in the world for the of like a certain
age, but if you're under the age of 30
and you're dealing with this [ __ ] I
promise this [ __ ] can still work out for
you. I have to engage with the fact that
a lot of us are not making it easy.
Getting roasted is never fun, right? But
when you grow up in black spaces, go to
black schools and black cultural
centers, you know that for the most
part, getting roasted is a right of
passage and in a twisted sense, maybe
even a act of affection. Not fully, not
always. There's some things to address
there. Again, shout out to the homie
Colormind who did a great analysis of
getting roasted and how it's not this
benign practice in black culture, but
for those in community, getting roasted
is just something that happens and it
doesn't always leave permanent damage.
But when you're outside of the
community, when you're one of these
[ __ ] that thinks I'm actually
the king of the blacks, and that's not
just a running joke that me and other
black people have about how y'all
perceive things incorrectly,
getting roasted to you might feel very
different. When you're already insecure
about your blackness, then having a
bunch of other black people roast you,
possibly your first ever black friend
group or peer group. That's not such a
benign thing. If you talk to black folks
who've been in that position, which I
have, I'll leave that video in the
description as well, they will tell you
how those experiences created more fear,
more confusion, more insecurity, and
more reason to avoid being around black
people. This is not to excuse the
unchecked antilack tendencies that come
out of some of these folks, but to say
that if they're coming around y'all, if
they're coming around you and your
friend group trying to engage with
blackness in the way that they have it
up until this point, it's because
they're genuinely trying to seek that
community that they probably didn't have
early in their lives. And they need
support and not sanction. Because the
flip side is that insecurity and trauma
is going to undergur and be used by
right-wing movements to separate them
further from regular black folks and
weaponize them against us. And I know I
hate that [ __ ] and I know y'all hate
that [ __ ] So, this is one way to
address it. When you're too harsh to
black folks from Vermont in your little
friend groups, you're just literally
feeding the trolls. You can look at some
of these fools in this 20V1 and see some
sadness in their eyes because they know
that they don't really want to be on
that side of the room, but they don't
know how not to be there. And that's why
I feel the way I feel about this topic
as a whole because the politics of black
conservatives is not a real story. It's
the internal conflict that's more
important and at least to me much more
interesting. And this is why I never
critically engage with black
conservative content. So please stop
sending this [ __ ] to me. Do not send me
any more videos or hot takes by insert
content creator here where they say
something ignorant about black people.
What the [ __ ] is wrong with y'all? Why
do y'all want me to experience this
trash? Do y'all not respect me? Am I a
slot tuber and I just don't realize it?
You understand that when you share this
and when I talk about it that just
spreads it more? Is it an insecurity in
you that you need to hear me say
something? Can't you just understand it
on your own or do you think there's some
truth there? And if you do, watch some
of my other [ __ ] videos. There's a
million black conservative and antilack
adjacent channels by black people who
basically make the same black culture is
bad video like every two weeks to keep
their numbers up. And anything else they
talk about will never be valued. And if
they ever step out of line, and we've
seen this numerous times with black
conservatives at this point, as soon as
they step out of line, they'll be pushed
to the side and replaced with the next
up. Because in reality, in all the ways
that matter, black conservative content
does not. It is only there as a coping
mechanism for their own internalized
[ __ ] or for them to get money or to
make a white audience that hates black
people happy that someone black is
saying it. Black conservatives do not
deserve to be put on the same playing
field of even an Amanda Sals. They do
not represent a viable political
ideology worthy of serious attention,
and they never will. always remember
this cuz it's about to happen again next
year that every election cycle for years
now they start doing the shitty well
what about black conservatives content
on the news knowing full well that the
data shows us that black conservatives
make up 10% of the black voting
population which is maybe 6% of all
black people which is less than like 1%
of all Americans yet they keep trottting
this [ __ ] out because it makes good
content because a lot of people most of
them white the rest of them dumb will
watch that is why unless I need the
Honey, you are never ever getting a real
black conservatives video from me. I'd
rather sell feet pics.
But I will talk about white folks
though, which is related to today's
sponsor, my short documentary talking
about white people, which you can only
find on my streaming service, Nebula.
Let's talk about today's sponsor,
Nebula. For those who don't know, Nebula
is created by artists like me to be a
way for us to maintain a creative vision
for our channels. And this means that in
between crowd-pleasing videos, I can
also make stuff that's more niche, like
a whole video about black nerd
aesthetics. If you know anything about
Nebula, then you know that we've had
some of the most talented and
forwardthinking creators around. And
because we have so much talent on our
roster, we have been expanding to say,
"What if we give this talent the
resources to go bigger and better than
what they thought possible?" There's the
Surrealist adventure, Night of the
Coconut, Dracula's ex-girlfriend from
Philosophy Tube, or if you just want
good oldfashioned video essays. We have
legends like Lindsay Ellis, who only
posts on Nebula and has made like 12
different exclusive videos for the site
as of today. There's hours of original
podcast, travel content, history
content, etc. Nebula has been developing
a wealth of content and talent that can
only be seen there, and most
significantly is doing all of this
independently. Nebula is owned by
creators and funded directly through
you, the viewer. We don't have any big
tech dollars propping us up that we have
to answer to and we want to keep it that
way so that we can continue to make the
exact thing that we want to make and to
be as weird and out there as we can. And
to do that, we rely on your support. So,
to help us on this evolution, please
click the link in the description or
follow the QR code on the screen to sign
up for a full year of Nebula for 40%
off. You'll be supporting the growth not
just of my channel, but of creators like
me to continue to go beyond the
limitations of YouTube and modern media
as a whole. Thank you for watching this
far into the video. Thank you to Nebula
for sponsoring the video. I'm FD
signifier and this has been light